♪By red walls and a dry well,
my crown gathers dust and frost♪
♪With a hoe and a patch of wasteland,
I sow the moonlight♪
♪Who says the Cold Palace
holds nothing but tears?♪
♪I choose to fill it with fragrant wine♪
♪Farming in the Cold Palace♪
♪Growing life's simple joys♪
♪Bins full of grain, jars full of wine♪
♪Better than dancing in silks♪
♪Farming in the Cold Palace♪
♪My heart longs for the world beyond♪
♪Tending a courtyard full of life♪
♪Come, share a cup with me♪
(Welcome to Cold Palace Refreshments)
=Farm Busily in the Cold Palace=
(Based on Hongshu.com's Novel
I'm Busy Farming in the Cold Palace)
=Episode 10=
Cao Zhongquan.
Bring a bridal cloth.
Yes, Your Majesty.
You said we wouldn't do anything.
Why do you need that?
This isn't the Cold Palace.
Female officials from the Palace Service
Office are outside keeping records.
The Empress Dowager keeps sending
women to my bed.
Let's make it convincing.
You're unbelievable.
First you took my money,
now you're using me as a shield.
Once you give up on leaving the palace,
I'll return your money.
Have you forgotten what you did
to the Lu family?
Keeping me this close...
Aren't you afraid I'll kill you?
Father!
Just in time, Empress.
No need to fetch my bride, then.
Guards!
- Here!
Take Lady Lu
to the Cold Palace.
Ji Wujue!
From heaven above to the depths below,
I'll haunt you even in death!
Father!
What if...
What if I didn't wipe out your family,
and there's more to this case?
would you stay?
I would.
Yes.
Good.
Then I promise
to solve this case soon
and give you and the Lu family answers.
All right.
Your Majesty.
The bridal cloth you requested.
What a backward custom.
I want to clear your name.
I want
to have every right
to bring you out of the Cold Palace.
(Emperors have always been fickle.)
(Could he really be in love with me?)
Close your eyes.
Are you scared?
No.
Then why pull away?
Just now,
I barely touched your lips.
I...
I didn't pull away.
You read bedtime stories, Your Majesty?
(First Meeting at Lixia Palace)
Isn't that my drawing?
Yes.
Not bad.
I've learned a lot from it.
But
the man in it
is a real eyesore.
Well, I...
I'd never seen you before.
I mistook him for you.
You...
Here.
No point wasting it.
His Majesty spent the night
with the Empress.
The Palace Service Office
will inspect the bridal cloth.
(Lixia Palace)
What did you say?
The Empress Dowager just sent word.
His Majesty chose someone tonight.
He summoned the woman from the Cold Palace
to attend him for the night.
I deserve death!
Please spare me!
Spare me!
Please calm down, Your Highness.
Enough.
Matron Chen.
Fetch my Shimmering Brocade.
I'll send it to Lady Lu as a gift.
Your Highness,
Wasn't that for your
coronation as Empress...
I won't get to wear it.
Give it to the Empress
for her burial shroud.
(Cold Palace)
One jade carving of twin lotuses,
two coral trees from the South Sea,
ten bolts of cloud brocade,
golden bird's nest...
Golden bird's nest?
Why is everything so heavy?
That cheapskate!
Not a single coin.
So afraid I'll run away.
Hmph.
(Invitation)
What's this?
Consort Yao sent it first thing today.
She invited you to Lixia Palace
to celebrate with you.
Why didn't you tell me sooner?
(Please Visit Lixia Palace)
She's definitely up to something.
My lady, you mustn't go.
A fox inviting a hen to dinner.
Of course I'm going.
Why wouldn't I?
My lady,
Haven't you got that backward?
I'm a little short on cash lately.
and someone's bringing me money.
(Lixia Palace)
(I couldn't see well from the roof.)
(She's got plenty of valuables.)
(Consort Yao is loaded.)
Pay your respects!
Looking for another beating?
Want me to remind you?
(I forgot how sharp-tongued she is.)
(And she hits without warning.)
I'm his wife. You're a consort.
So who should be bowing to whom?
Greetings, Your Majesty.
That's better.
(An abandoned woman in the Cold Palace,)
(a disgraced official's daughter,)
(gets a little favor from His Majesty)
(and dares challenge me?)
Well?
What do you want?
Matron Chen.
Bring out the Shimmering Brocade.
Yes.
I hear His Majesty favors you.
This gift is for you.
This Shimmering Brocade
was dyed with moth-wing powder
by Western Regions artisans.
It takes 1,000 days to make one bolt.
Best of all,
It reveals a special pattern
in moonlight.
Moth powder?
Wouldn't it itch like crazy?
(Why not just give me money?)
(The Empress Dowager gave me this.)
(You have no right to it.)
(She'll have your hide.)
(Even His Majesty won't save you.)
(I can't just ask for money.)
(How do I turn this rag into cash?)
My dear sister,
don't you want to know
why His Majesty favors only me?
Are you trying to provoke me?
What makes you say that?
Of course not.
We're all sisters here.
Naturally, I want His Majesty
to share his favor
and have plenty of heirs.
You're really that generous?
(Royal Bedroom Secrets)
This is
His Majesty's one-of-a-kind book,
hidden under his pillow.
It's how I won his favor.
Just 5,000 taels,
and it's
yours.
His Majesty reads things like this?
I don't believe you.
Look.
(First Meeting at Lixia Palace)
That's his handwriting, right?
It really is.
(First Meeting at Lixia Palace)
Lixia Palace?
Could he truly care for me?
Of course he does.
I'm just the budget version.
To be His Majesty's woman,
you need the whole package.
Look.
This fabric is thin but not sheer.
I can rework it
into a fitted summer dress.
Just add another 5,000 taels.
What outfit costs 5,000 taels?
One night of passion is worth a fortune.
It's bedroom fun. You get it?
Would His Majesty really like this?
Would I lie to you?
Twice the effect, half the effort.
Go.
Open my private treasury.
Your Highness!
Yao,
look.
Just enough to tease.
His Majesty will adore you.
Hesitate, and I'll sell to Consort Lan.
Don't regret it later.
Quickly!
Go get 10,000 taels for her.
You really are something.
If this wins His Majesty's favor,
I shall
I'll repay you for the rest of my life.
(Yun Banknote)
10,000 taels
Think nothing of it.
Then I'll
be on my way.
Matron Chen, see her out.
No need.
My work here is done.
No need for fame or glory.
Bye!
Your Highness,
will you really befriend Lady Lu?
And the Empress Dowager?
I was just saying that.
In this harem, it's all self-interest.
There's no real friendship.
Your Majesty.
The Empress went to Lixia Palace.
Consort Yao invited her?
Yes, Your Majesty.
Consort Yao
isn't easy to deal with.
Her attendants are no pushovers either.
Do you want to go check on her?
Hmph.
Since when are you on Lu Yunluo's side?
I would never, Your Majesty!
It's just...
It's just that, in this palace,
only the Empress can make you smile.
She certainly is different.
Others fight for favor,
while she grows crops,
studies the stars,
and runs businesses.
She's full of tricks.
How could Consort Yao beat her?
I worried for nothing.
But you did remind me.
If I intend to restore her as Empress,
she does need more attendants.
You've already assigned her
your best guards.
Jia and Yi are men, after all.
They can't tend to her personal needs.
Go to the chancellor's estate.
See if any trusted servants remain.
If so,
send them to serve her
in the Cold Palace.
As you command.
♪By red walls and a dry well,
my crown gathers dust and frost♪
♪With a hoe and a patch of wasteland,
I sow the moonlight♪
♪Who says the Cold Palace
holds nothing but tears?♪
♪I choose to fill it with fragrant wine♪
♪Cool dew, starry nights,
wheat sprouts in my hands♪
♪I shape fields, not painted brows,
and fill them with hope♪
♪Gold and silver bloom from the soil♪
♪I smile as the world storms on♪
♪No finery to rival spring♪
♪All I wish for are waves of green♪
♪Where is beauty found?♪
♪Just lift your eyes and see♪
♪Farming in the Cold Palace♪
♪Growing life's simple joys♪
♪Bins full of grain, jars full of wine♪
♪Better than dancing in silks♪
♪Farming in the Cold Palace♪
♪My heart longs for the world beyond♪
♪Tending a courtyard full of life♪
♪Come, share a cup with me♪